A Guide to the Papers of the Carter and Wellford Family of Sabine Hall 1650-1918
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I: Correspondence of Landon Carter
  - Elizabeth Wormeley Beverley to Landon Carter 1765 May 1 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Charles Carter of "Corotoman" to Landon Carter 1765 May 20 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Maria Carter to Landon Carter (copy) 1765 June 2 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Richard Henry Lee to Landon Carter (copy) 1765 June 22 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - William Churchill to Landon Carter 1765 June 25 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Judith Banks to Landon Carter 1765 June (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Landon Carter of "Cleve" to Landon Carter 1765 July 13 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Richard Henry Lee to Landon Carter 1765 August 15 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Richard Henry Lee to Landon Carter 1765 September 20 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Landon Carter to Jonas Greene 1765 November 4 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Landon Carter to Mr. of Great Britain 1765 November 30 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Robert Carter of "Nomini" to Landon Carter 1765 December 27 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Robert Carter Nicholas to Landon Carter 1766 January 27 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Richard Henry Lee to Landon Carter 1766 February 2 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Charles Carter to Landon Carter 1766 February 10 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Richard Henry Lee to Landon Carter 1766 February 24 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Judith Banks to Landon Carter 1766 March 22 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Charles Carter of "Corotoman" to Landon Carter 1766 August 4 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - John Tayloe to Landon Carter 1766 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - John Tayloe to Robert Wormeley Carter 1767 March 20 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Landon Carter, Jr. to Landon Carter ca. 1767 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - John Tayloe to Landon Carter 1768 January 3 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1768 January 6 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1768 February 26 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1768 May 21 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Ralph Wormeley, Jr. to Landon Carter 1768 June 10 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1768 July 8 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1768 August 28 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Landon Carter to Norborne Berkeley, Lord Botetourt 1768 November 1 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Rebecca Tayloe to Landon Carter 1768 November 5 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1768 November 26 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Richard Henry Lee to Landon Carter 1768 December 8 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Charles Carter of "Corotoman" to Landon Carter 1768 December 25 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Peyton Randolph to Landon Carter [1768] (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Landon Carter to an old friend 1769 May 14 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Peter Pelham to Landon Carter 1769 December 8 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Charles Carter of "Corotoman" to Landon Carter 1769 December 25 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Landon Carter to Alexander Purdie and John Dixon 1769 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Landon Carter to "Two in the Corner" 1770 April 9 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - William Rind to Landon Carter 1770 April 13 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Charles Carter of "Corotoman" to Landon Carter 1770 April 24 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1770 June 8 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1770 June 17 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1770 June 22 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - John Tayloe to Landon Carter 1770 August 3 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Richard Henry Lee to Landon Carter (copy) 1771 January 17 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Francis Lightfoot Lee to Landon Carter 1771 February 13 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Robert Beverley to Landon Carter (copy) 1771 February 26 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Master Landon Carter to Landon Carter 1771 March 4 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Ralph Wormeley, Jr. to Landon Carter 1771 March 6 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - John Tayloe to Landon Carter 1771 March 31 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Richard Henry Lee to Landon Carter (copy) 1771 April 18 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - John Tayloe to Landon Carter 1771 September 23 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1771 September (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1771 October 6 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Robert Carter Nicholas to Landon Carter 1771 October 15 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Master Landon Carter to Landon Carter 1771 November 10 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - William Fitzhugh to Landon Carter 1771 December 20 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Owen Griffith to Landon Carter 1771 December 20 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Robert Beverley to Landon Carter 1771 December 23 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1771 December (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1771 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Landon Carter to Virginia Gazette1771 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Richard Henry Lee to Landon Carter (copy) 1772 March 7 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1772 March 20 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1772 March 30 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1772 March 31 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Richard Henry Lee to Landon Carter (copy) 1772 March 31 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Dr. Walter Jones to Landon Carter 1772 April 24 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1772 June 4 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Landon Carter to Edward Montague 1772 June 5 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Landon Carter to William Rind 1772 August (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Robert Wormeley, Jr. to Landon Carter 1772 September 24 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Edward Montague to Landon Carter (copy) 1772 September 30 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Robert Wormeley, Jr. to Landon Carter 1772 October 7 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Richard Henry Lee to Landon Carter (copy) 1772 October 9 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Dr. Walter B. Jones to Landon Carter (copy) 1772 December 1 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Dr. Walter B. Jones to Landon Carter 1772 December 1 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Charles Carter of "Corotoman" to Landon Carter 1772 December 20 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Charles Carter of "Corotoman" to Landon Carter 1773 January 9 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - John Tayloe to Landon Carter 1773 February 22 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - John Tayloe to Landon Carter 1773 February 22 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - John Wormeley to Landon Carter 1773 August 23 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Dr. Walter B. Jones to Landon Carter 1773 August 25 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1773 August (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Ralph Wormeley to Landon Carter 1773 September 18 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Landon Carter to William Rind 1773 October 6 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1773 November 6 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Charles Carter of "Corotoman" to Landon Carter 1773 December 19 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Landon Carter to Robert Wormeley Carter and Francis Lightfoot Lee 1773 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Landon Carter to Ralph Wormeley (copy) 1774 January 25 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Landon Carter to Alexander Purdie and John Dixon 1774 February 14 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - John Tayloe to Landon Carter 1774 April 23 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Richard Henry Lee to Landon Carter (copy) 1774 April 25 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1774 May 3 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1774 May 7 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1774 May 8 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1774 May 10 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1774 May 13 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Dr. Walter B. Jones to Landon Carter 1774 May 19 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Dr. Walter B. Jones to Landon Carter 1774 June 17 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Moore Fauntleroy to Landon Carter 1774 July 10 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Landon Carter to Virginia Gazette1774 July 18 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Robert Beverley to Landon Carter (copy) 1774 July 27 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Alexander Purdie to Landon Carter 1774 August 3 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Archibald Ritchie to Landon Carter 1774 September 11 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Landon Carter to "My friend" ca. 1774 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Alexander Purdie to Landon Carter 1775 February 21 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Landon Carter to Richard Henry Lee 1775 February 25 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Landon Carter to Alexander Purdie 1775 May 10 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1775 July 29 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1775 August 5 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Robert Wormeley Carter to Landon Carter 1775 August 10 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1775 August 17 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Alexander Purdie to Landon Carter 1775 October 13 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Dr. Walter B. Jones to Landon Carter 1775 October 14 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Dr. Walter B. Jones to Landon Carter 1775 October 14 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Edmund Pendleton to Landon Carter (copy) 1775 October 14 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Alexander Purdie to Landon Carter 1775 November 1 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - John Page, Vice-President of the Committee on Public Safety to the Chairman of the Lancaster Committee 1775 November 4 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Landon Carter to "the Committee" 1775 December 5 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Dr. Walter B. Jones to Landon Carter 1775 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Landon Carter to "Gentlemen of the Grand Jury" (copy) ante 1776 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Dr. Walter B. Jones to Landon Carter 1776 January 16 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Major Josiah Parker to Landon Carter 1776 April 14 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Raleigh Colston to Landon Carter 1776 April 22 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - John Upshaw to Landon Carter 1776 April 27 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1776 June 11 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Landon Carter, Jr. to Landon Carter 1776 July 19 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1776 July 19 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Betty Randolph to Landon Carter 1776 September 16 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Landon Carter to Alexander Purdie 1776 September (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Philip Key to Richard Henry Lee 1777 April 20 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Rev. Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1778 May 3 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Samuel Chase, Congress, to Governor Thomas Johnston 1778 May 4 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Isaac W. Giberne to Landon Carter 1770s (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Landon Carter to John Boughton, overseer at "Ring's Neck" 1770s (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Landon Carter to fellow American 1770s (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Landon Carter to William Rind 1770s (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Landon Carter to "Dear Sir" 1770s (Box-folder 1:16)
- Series II: Financial and Legal Papers of Landon Carter
  - Patent from William Berkeley to William Underwood 1650 May 22 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Survey for William Underwood's Patent 1650 May 22 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Deed of sale from William Underwood to Captain Richard Loes and Rice E. Jones 1659 November 2 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Patent from William Berkeley to Richard Webley 1664-1665 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Deed of sale from Walter Pavey to Thomas Fuller 1680 August 9 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Deed of sale from Walter Pavey to John Rice 1680-1681 January 3 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Plat and description by surveyor William Moseley 1683 June 13 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Deed of sale from Walter Pavey and Mary Pavey to Thomas Fuller 1683 September 4 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Indenture of release from Richard Glover to Walter Pavey 1683 January 21 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture from Walter Pavey and Mary Pavey to John Rice 1683 January 28; 1864 April 18 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Col Wm. Lloyd's survey of land for 1223 acres, by William Moseley 1683-1684 February 27 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture from Walter Pavey and Mary Pavey to John Rice 1683-1684 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Will of John Rice 1693 October 6 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - William Colston... 1695 June 5 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Deed of sale from John Champe to Col. William Pierce 1698 April 26 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Map of Sabine Hall Estate early 1700s (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Map of Sabine Hall Estate early 1700s (Oversize Oversize)
  - Plat of land surveyed by Henry Ashton for Col. Robert Carter early 1700s (Oversize Oversize)
  - Unidentified survey notations by Landon Carter early 1700s (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Indenture fragment early 1700s (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Grant from Robert Carter, agent for Lady Catherine Fairfax, to Sharshall Grasty 1712 August 27 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture of release from Sharshall Grasty to Robert Carter 1713 September 29 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Bond for performance of covenant from Sharshall Grasty to Robert Carter 1713 October 15 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Survey map and description of land that Daniel McCarty bought from John Rice and Webley Pavey, by surveyor John Coppridge 1714 April 28 (Oversize Oversize)
  - James Alderson to Daniel McCarty 1714 August 2 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Indenture of lease from Webley Pavey to Daniel McCarty 1714 August 30 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture of sale from Webley Pavey to Daniel McCarty 1714 August 31 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture of sale from Benjamin Hinds and Mary Hinds to Daniel McCarty 1714 November 30 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture of release from Webley Pavey to Daniel McCarty 1714-1715 January 4 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture of release from John Minor to John Champe, with subsequent dates July 30, 1732 and September 4, 1738 1715 March 31 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Survey of "Green's Land" according to Captain Barber 1723 November 14-15 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture of lease from Marmaduke Beckwith to Richard and Ann Doggitt for one year, subsequent date February 28, 1734 1727 October 31 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Map and description of "Ring's Quarter" by surveyor Robert Brooke for Maj. Benjamin Robinson and Elizabeth Wormeley (copy) 1729 December 18 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Testimonial given at Gerard Court (fragment) 1731 January 7 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Map and description on Shenandoah River by surveyor John Warner for Landon Carter 1731 May 8 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - "A plat of the land held by Col. William Lloyd in Mangorika and the Fork," acquired about this time by Landon Carter, by surveyor William Moseley 1731 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Deed from Walter Pavey to William Lloyd (fragment) ca. 1731 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Bond for performance of covenants from John Champe and John Champe, Jr. to Edward Barradall 1732 July 20 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Indenture of lease from John Champe and John Champe, Jr. to Edward Barradall 1732 July 20 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture 1733 May 23 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture of lease from Edward Barradall to Landon Carter 1733 May 28 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture of lease from Edward Barradall to Landon Carter 1733 May 29 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture from Marmaduke Beckwith to Landon Carter 1734 May 27 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Shop note from Edward Athawes, bought of Martha Williams for Robert Carter, Jr.'s Estate 1734 January 2 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Bond for performance of covenants from Marmaduke Beckwith to Landon Carter 1734 February 28 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture from Marmaduke Beckwith to Landon Carter (copy) 1734 May 27 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Report from Edward Athawes to John and Charles Carter (copy) 1735 January 12 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Survey of tract of land by Landon Carter, Col. John Tayloe, William Deggar, Maj. William Fauntleroy and others 1735 January 20 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Indenture from Elizabeth Beckwith to Landon Carter 1735 February 28 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Edward Athawes to John Carter and Landon Carter (copy) 1735 July 22 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Bond for performance of covenants from Edward Barradell to Landon Carter 1735 August 5 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Land Title Papers 1735 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Report from Edward Athawes to John and Charles Carter 1736 June 8 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Report on "Nomini" from Edward Athawes to John and Charles Carter 1736 December 20 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Report from Edward Athawes to John, Charles and Landon Carter 1736 December 31 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Report from Edward Athawes to John, Charles and Landon Carter (copy) 1737 July 5 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Report from Edward Athawes to John and Charles Carter (copy) 1737/8 March 10 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Report from Edward Athawes to John and Charles Carter 1737/8 March 10 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - Report from Edward Athawes to John and Charles Carter (copy) 1738 January 10 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Daniel McCarty acknowledgment of receipt of money to Landon Carter 1738 June 30 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Report from Daniel McCarty to Landon Carter 1738 August 7 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Bond for performance of covenants from Dennis McCarty and Daniel McCarty to Landon Carter 1738 September 4 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture of sale from Dennis and Sarah McCarty, and Daniel McCarty to Landon Carter 1738 September 4 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Essay of land lately belonging to Maj. Dennis McCarty (copy) 1738 November 13 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Names and values of four slaves from Dennis McCarty to Landon Carter 1738 November 14 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Map and survey by surveyor Thomas Barber for "Riverside Field" 1738 November 14 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Report from Edward Athawes to John Carter (copy) 1738 December 22 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Report from William Lovey to Landon Carter 1738 December 28 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Memoranda listing ownership of the William Underwood patent ca. 1738 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Commission to Captain Thomas Wright Belfield and Gilbert Hamilton to examine Sarah McCarty privately [to determine if she agreed to the sale of land to Landon Carter that she and her husband owned] 1739 August 6 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Report from Edward Athawes to John and Charles Carter (copy) 1739 April 16 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Deed from Dennis McCarty to Landon Carter (fragment) 1739 April 23 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Report of arrival of slave ship from John Carter to Landon Carter 1739 June 14 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - John Carter to Landon Carter 1739 July 11 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Philip Lightfoot to Landon Carter (copy) 1739 July 30 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Will of John Carter 1741 January 2 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Report from Edward Athawes to John Carter 1741 March 18 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Description of a plant on the summit of a hill by Landon Carter 1741 May (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Indenture of sale from Edward Spencer to Landon Carter 1741 November 2 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture of release from John and Mary White to Benjamin Rust 1746 July 7 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Report from Charles Carter to Landon Carter 1747 May 6 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - "Survey of the land between Carter and Rust" by William Garland for Landon Carter 1750 September 15 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Indenture of release from John and Ann White to Benjamin Rust 1752 November 6 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Map and description by surveyor William Garland for Landon Carter (copy) 1752 December 16 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Will of Benjamin Rust 1754 February 19 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Survey and map of part of the Sabine Hall estate by surveyor William Garland for John Harford 1754 July 2 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Bond for conveyance of mill and land from William Garland to Landon Carter 1755 October 23 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Survey and map of "Fork Land" 1759 July 10 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Request from George William Fairfax for Landon Carter to pay balance on quit rent 1760 April 10 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Receipt for quit rents from Jonathan Beckwith to Landon Carter (copy) 1760 May 14 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Quit rent account from Thomas Bryan Martin to Landon Carter (copy) 1760 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Minutes of the Proceedings of the Lords Commissioners for Trade and Plantations by Landon Carter 1763 February 1 & 2 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Quit rent account from Thomas Bryan Martin to Landon Carter (copy) 1763 May 11 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Landon Carter to Thomas Bryan Martin re quit rent (copy) 1763 May 27 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Richard Parker to Landon Carter (copy) 1763 July 1 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Edward Montague to Arthur Lee 1763 July 5 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Landon Carter to Thomas Bryan Martin (copy) 1763 July 18 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Report receipt of orders from Richard Corbin to Landon Carter 1764 January 24 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Robert Carter of "Nomini" to Landon Carter (copy) 1764 February 12 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Ralph Wormeley to Landon Carter 1764 March 9 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - "A Case stated as to the Right of Action in the Plaintiff" ca. 1764 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Promissory note from William Churchill to Landon Carter 1765 June 25 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Royal enactment confirming an act of the Virginia General Assembly pertaining to the lands of Charles Carter bequeathed to him by Robert "King" Carter 1766 February 10 (Oversize Oversize)
  - "Museum Rusticum" with notes made by Landon Carter 1766 March (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Landon Carter to Thomas Lord Fairfax re quit rents (copy) 1766 April 10 (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Thomas Bryan Martin to Landon Carter 1766 August 20 (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Landon Carter to Thomas Bryan Martin re George and Charles Carter's lands (copy) 1766 September 24 (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Indenture of release from John and Elizabeth Beale to John Taylor, Landon Carter and William Fauntleroy 1766 November 29 (Oversize Oversize)
    land for glebe and poor house
  - Landon Carter to Thomas Lord Fairfax (copy) 1767 September 29 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Landon Carter to Thomas Lord Fairfax re quit rents (copy) 1768 June 20 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Royal enactment confirming an act of the Virginia General Assembly pertaining to the settlement of the estate of Charles Carter of "Cleve" 1768 June 29 (Oversize Oversize)
  - Quit rent bill from Thomas Bryan Martin to Landon Carter 1768 July 12 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Landon Carter to Thomas Lord Fairfax re quit rents (copy) 1768 July 26 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - George Mason to Landon and Charles Carter, Jr. as executor of the estate of Charles Carter 1770 May 14 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Plat and description of "Juggs" by Griffin Garland for Landon Carter 1770 July 25 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Landon Carter's testimony over land ownership (copy) 1770 August 2 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - "Address to the Court, by One of the Judges" by Landon Carter ca. 1770 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Landon Carter to Thomas Lord Fairfax re quit rents (copy) 1772 October 6-12 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Thomas Bryan Martin to Landon Carter re quit rents (copy) 1772 October 12 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Landon Carter to William Fairfax re quit rents (copy) 1772 November 3 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Landon Carter to William Fairfax re quit rent 1772 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - Landon Carter's list of his papers (copy) 1773 March 30 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - "Tithables belonging to Landon Carter in Lunenberg Parish in Richmond County" 1773 June 10 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Landon Carter to the Proprietor's Office of the Northern Neck (copy) 1773 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Thomas Bryan Martin to Landon Carter re quit rents (copy) 1773 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Landon Carter to Thomas Lord Fairfax re quit rents (copy) 1773 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - "Intended as a Paper of Information to Mr. Richard Parker" (copy) 1773 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Landon Carter to Richard Parker re quit rents 1773 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - Thomas Bryan Martin to Landon Carter re quit rents (copy) 1774 November 3 (Box-folder 1:28)
  - Plat of Gwinn Island with notes by Landon Carter 1776 (Box-folder 1:28)
  - Outlawry of Nassau, escaped slave (copy) 1777 October 19 (Box-folder 1:28)
  - Deposition of Landon Carter; Summons to Thomas Beale (copy) 1778 October 5 & November 12 (Box-folder 1:28)
  - "An Inventory of the Estate of Landon Carter..." with typescript 1779 February (Box-folder 1:28)
- Series III: Papers of Landon Carter
  - Landon Carter to "The Gentlemen Planters of Virginia" 1753 October 12 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - John Woodbridge to "The Freeholders of Richmond County" 1765 July 5 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Verses relative to Col. Landon Carter enclosed to Col. Tayloe 1768 November (Box-folder 2:1)